Andrew J. Milewski III

Andrew.Milewski3@gmail.com · 970-214-0774 http://www.linkedin.com/pub/andy-milewski3

IT Leader · Strategist · Orchestrator

Summary

Senior IT Leader with broad technical and leadership skills focused on DevOps, Container adoption, Private Cloud, Data Center operations, Enterprise Systems Management, Infrastructure, and Organizational Transformation and Strategy

Business-minded approach including more than 18 years of experience with increasing responsibilities for Management and "Hands On" support of Information Technology Services in Private Cloud, Container as a Service, Lab Automation, Virtualization, Cyber-Security, Data Center Operations

People-minded individual with ability to build the necessary relationships to support business goals and expected outcomes across multi-level global organizations

Service Oriented Leader with ability to demand and deliver excellence in management and outcomes

 $\label{eq:container} DevOps \cdot Container \ as \ a \ Service \cdot Enterprise \ Architecture \ and \ Design \cdot Datacenter \cdot IaaS \cdot PaaS \cdot Virtualization \cdot Lab \ Automation \cdot Vendor \ Management \cdot Budgetary \ Operational \ Excellence \cdot Cybersecurity \cdot Sales \ Enablement \cdot Operational \ Efficiencies \cdot Program \ Management \cdot Operations \ Management \cdot Project \ and \ Resource \ Management \cdot IT \ Automation \cdot Systems \ and \ Network \ Management \ Automation \cdot Systems \ and \ Network \ Management \ Automation \cdot Systems \ and \ Network \ Management \ Automation \cdot Systems \ Autom$

Professional Experience

Hewlett-Packard Enterprise 3404 E Harmony Road, Fort Collins, Colorado, 80528 2000 – 2018

Senior Engineering Manager and Enterprise Architect, HPE Global IT, Cloud and Containers **2016 – 2018**

- Define, Design and Deliver against vision of Containers and Cloud Native adoption within HPE for Global IT, Product R&D, and HPE.NeXT transformation initiatives
- Deployed Docker Enterprise for Stateless Container as a Service and Mesosphere DC/OS for Data Pipelining as a Service. Jenkins to automate the lifecycle
- Delivering upon the notion of Infrastructure as Code and DevOps to accelerate change and adoption
- Lead HPE on HPE initiatives to showcase how Hewlett Packard Enterprise uses its own solutions to solve internal IT challenges

Senior Technical Program Manager, HPE EG CTO, Shared Labs

2014 - 2016

- Drove strategy and adoption of Hybrid IT for R&D community targeting DevOps methodologies to enable transformation of applications to modern, micro-services-based architectures
- Partnered with Global IT and EG R&D Business Units on strategy, incubation, and Governance to accelerate adoption
- Lead program to enable Products teams with transformation of Build Pipelines to Continuous Integration and Delivery model
- Implemented Cloud System Enterprise to enable IaaS and PaaS capabilities for Developers in Shared Services model
- Implemented Docker Enterprise Edition for IT4IT and IT4RND Transformation initiatives
- Implemented and Operationalized Docker Trusted Registry for Pan-HPE use
- Lead HPE on HPE program providing experiences documented in Reference Configurations for benefit of EG Customers
- Program Management and Infrastructure Architect for initiative to develop Infrastructure as
 Code Solution using HPE Synergy, OneView, Terraform, Ansible resulting in reference architecture used by HPE
 Sales organization helping close several million-dollar plus deals

Senior Technical Program Manager, HP EG CTO, Lab Space Planning and Operations **2012** – **2014**

- Drive Operational Efficiencies and Strategy of multiple Tier 1 R&D Datacenters achieving Energy Star rating of 97 or better
- Drive adoption and compliance of Network Security for more than 150 R&D Network compartments
 and associated systems to reduce risk to HP Intellectual Property while enabling the organization to deliver against
 Business objectives
- Implemented Virtual Infrastructure resulting in improvements in Cyber-Security, Network Security, Remote Access and Lab Space Utilization
- Evolved Program from being disruptive to the Businesses supported to one that works on behalf of the Business and its associated objectives

Engineering Manager, HP Software Global Demonstration and Enablement Infrastructures

2007 - 2011

- M&A activities driving consolidation of Peregrine, Mercury and Opsware Demo & Training Infrastructure Programs into one centralized Enterprise Lab for HP Software Organization with zero downtime or impact to Technical Sales Operations
- Conceptualized, planned, managed and launched two Private Clouds used for delivery of Software Demonstration and Training, reducing costs, increasing agility and expanding delivery. Created the largest Implementation in the world based on Surgient Cloud Automation Platform at the time
- Expanded Infrastructure in support of key initiative for remote virtualized Training Development and Delivery reducing costs by over 90% while scaling out to support HP Employee Enablement activities

Senior Solutions Architect, HP Software Worldwide Global Enablement Solution Center

2006 - 2007

• Designed and Implemented Private Cloud to support Sales Operations and Enablement activities for HP Software Presales Consultants and Solution Architects supporting more than \$1 Billion in Revenue

Systems Architect and Engineer, HP OpenView Software Demonstration Center **2003** - **2006**

 Conceptualized and Established Remote/Virtual Software Demonstration Center to reduce costs and provide Self-service delivery of demo system resources, allowing for 10+-hours/month increases in "time in front of the Customer" helping increasing revenue from \$600 M to \$1 Billion

Education

Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80524 Bachelor of Arts in Social Science

Certification

VMware Certified Associate – Data Center Virtualization: License 272827077 ITIL v2 Foundations

Skills

- Collaboration
- DevOps
- Communication
- Ability to build relationships
- Problem Solving
- Leadership
- Data Services
- Data Center Operations